You may have been on duty all night, Fewsham,
你可能是值班值了一夜, Fewsham
but that's no excuse for this kind of slipping up!
但那也不能成为这种失误的借口！
- They weren't major hold-ups.
- Kelly was going mad on Earth Control!
- 并没有出现大的拥塞  - Kelly 在地球控制中心那边都发飙了
She would!
她会的！
I'm sorry, Fewsham, but it's my head in the noose as well, you know!
对不起, Fewsham, 但这事我也脱不了干系, 知道吗？
I know! I'm sorry.
我知道！对不起
Oh, all right.
哦, 算了
All right, go on. You'd better get back to Earth.
好吧, 继续．你最好回地球去
(WAILING BEEP)
Now what?!
怎么回事？
It has no air locks.
这里没有气闸(fixm)
- Who's there?
- No one.
- 谁在哪儿？  - 没谁
Then how come the air locks are in use?
那为什么气闸有人使用？
(MAN SCREAMS IN TERROR)
Phipps! What is it? What's happened?
Phipps！怎么回事？发生了什么？
Come on, man!
快点, 伙计！
(TERRIFIED SCREAM)
Close the door!
把门关上！
(POUNDING, CLANGING FOOTSTEPS)
Don't move, anybody! Don't do anything!
别动, 所有人！什么也不要做！
Harvey, don't!
Harvey, 别！
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(POUNDING, CLANGING FOOTSTEPS)
(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
The Seeds of Death
No! I refuse!
不, 我拒绝！
(RASPING WHISPER) You will be wise to co-operate at once,
聪明的话, 立即合作
otherwise you will be destroyed!
否则你就会被消灭！
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Well, I suppose that leaves me no alternative.
这, 我觉得我没有别的选择了
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
Don't do it, sir!
别啊, 头儿！
(RASPING WHISPER) Silence!
安静！
There's a certain element of risk.
这里会有一定的风险
(RASPING WHISPER) You are wasting time!
你实在浪费时间！
(HISSING, LABOURED BREATHING)
(RASPING WHISPER) What is happening?
怎么回事？
I'm afraid there's been a fault.
恐怕这里出故障了
The circuit's overloaded.
线路过载了
Very unfortunate.
非常不幸
(RASPING WHISPER) You deliberately sabotaged this apparatus!
你蓄意破坏了这个装置！
Kill him!
杀了他！
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(JAMIE) Hey! Quite a place, isn't it?
嘿！不错的地方啊, 是不？
(DOCTOR) Oh, my word!
哦, 天哪
- Look at the size of this one, Doc!
- Yes!
- 看看这东西有多大, 博士！  - 是啊！
(ZOE) Oh, Doctor, look!
噢, 博士, 你看！
Doctor, look.
博士, 翘翘
- Now, Zoe...
- (BEEPING)
现在, Zoe...
What's that?
什么东西？
(MAN) Travel Mat is the ultimate form of travel.
T-Mat 物传系统是传送物质的最终形式
Control centre of the present at the moment is the moon, serving all major cities on Earth.
当前控制中心在月球上, 为地球各大城市提供服务
Travel Mat provides an instantaneous means of public travel,
T-Mat 物传系统提供的一种即时传送能力
and transports raw materials and vital food supplies to all parts of the world.
将原材料料和重要的食物供应传送到世界各地
- (JAMIE) Travel Mat? Sounds like a flying carpet!
- Hush, hush, Jamie, keep silence
- 物传系统？听起来像是个飞毯! - 嘘, 嘘, Jamie, 安静
Travel Mat supersedes all conventional forms of transports
T-Mat 物传系统取代了所有传统形式的运输
using the principle of dematerialisation at the point of departure,
它的工作原理是将物质在出发点进行反物质化分解
and rematerialisation at the point of arrival in special cubicles.
然后再在到达点的特殊格子间里面进行物质化聚合
Departure and arrival are almost instantaneous.
出发和到达基本上是瞬时的
Faster than light!
比光还快！
Although The system is still in its early stage,
虽然这个系统还在早期阶段
it is completely automated and fool-proofed against power failure.
它已经实现完全自动化, 并且可以避免在停电时带来灾难
Well, we have our own system, thank you, only it isn't foolproof!
哦, 我们有了自己的系统, 谢谢你, 只是它不是防呆的(fixme)
Jamie, I think that's just a tiny bit...
Jamie, 我觉得那只是一个小问题
You saw what happened to your superior.
你看到了你的上级怎么样了
You would do well to co-operate.
你会乖乖合作的
Killing him didn't do you any good.
杀死他不会给你们带来任何好处
- Would you do as I ask?
- There is nothing I can do!
- 你会按我的要求行事吗？  - 这里我做不了什么了
- You do not want to die?
- I'm not that good enough a technician!
- 你不想死吧？  - 我是个不怎么样的技工！
- It needs an expert!
- But you are second in command here.
- 这需要一个专家！  - 但你是这里的二把手
- Yes, but...
- You must have certain abilities.
- 是的, 但是...  - 你肯定有些能力
- You must know what needs to be done.
- In theory, yes.
- 你肯定知道需要搞定什么  - 理论上来说, 是的
Then you will do it!
那你就得做！
He'll only make it worse!
他只会把事情搞砸！
What is their status here?
他们在这里是做什么的？
Maintenance. Second-class technicians.
维护．二级技工
There's only one person that could really put all these things right, and she is at Earth Control./?
只有一个人能让这一切恢复正常, 而她在地球控制中心
- Without her, it can't be done!
- Who is this specialist?
- 没有她, 这搞不定！  - 这个专家是谁？
Miss Kelly, technical co-ordinator. But there's no way to reach her. T-Mat is not working.
Kelly 小姐, 技术协调员．但我们没法接触到她, T-Mat 不工作了
- But you have a video link.
- Yes, but Osgood wrecked that, too!
- 但你们有视频线路  - 是的, 但 Osgood 把它也搞坏了！
So, there is no means to communicate with Earth?
这么说, 没有方法跟地球联系了？
No, you've cut us off completely!
没有, 你们把我们完全切断了！
In that case, you are useless!
这么说来, 你们都没有用了！
You will all be destroyed!
你们全部都要被消灭！
There's the emergency T-Mat link!
还有一条 T-Mat 紧急线路！
It only operates from here to Earth!
它只是供这里和地球之间使用的的！
Then you will activate the apparatus...
那你激活这个装置...
..at once!
马上！
- It's damaged, too!
- The technicians will help repair it.
- 它也坏了！  - 技术人员将帮忙修好它
- We won't help you. Neither will he!
- Then he will die!
- 我们不会帮你的, 他也不会！  - 那他就死了！
No more money, no more facilities.
没有了钱, 也就没有了设备
A life's work abandoned, just like that. All thanks to T-Mat!
一辈子的成果被遗弃了, 就这样．都拜 T-Mat 所赐!
I can understand your sense of bitterness, Professor./?
我理解你的痛苦, 教授
Very short-sighted of the government to put all their eggs in one basket!
目光短浅的政府把所有的鸡蛋放到了一个篮子里面！
You still haven't told me who you are and what you're doing here!
你还没有告诉我你们是谁, 在这里干什么！
(WAILING BLEEP) That's the main door alarm! What's going on?
那是主门在告警！怎么回事？
Professor Daniel Eldred, well, well, well!
Danile Eldred 教授, 好, 好, 好
Radnor, come to see how your spies are getting on?
Randor, 你是来看你那些间谍有什么进展的吗？
I'm sorry? We've not met. My name's Radnor. This is Miss Kelly.
抱歉, 我们没见过．我叫 Radnor, 这是 Kelly 小姐
Oh, how do you do?
哦, 你好
This is Zoe, Jamie, and I'm the Doctor.
这是 Zoe, Jamie, 而我是博士
Don't pretend you don't know them!
别假装你不认识他们！
I can assure you I've never met them before in my life.
我可以保证我这辈子从来没有见过他们
I see. I find three strangers prowling around in my museum.
明白了．我发现这三个陌生人在我的博物馆里面鬼鬼祟祟
and by the merest coincidence, you turn up on their very heels!
非常巧合的是, 你后脚就出现了
I can assure you I merely wanted a chat with a very old friend.
我可以向你保证, 我只不过是想跟一个老朋友聊一聊
Well, you've done without a chat for a good many years.
噢, 很多年不聊你也过来了
Old times. Friendships don't die.
时光流逝, 但友情不会逝去
Our friendship ended the day that you walked out of my laboratory
我们的友情在你走出我的实验室的时候就死了！
and joined the government administration on T-Mat!
在你加入政府的 T-Mat 管理方的时候就死了！
Different men, different careers!
不同的性格, 不同的职业发展！
Yes, but you knew which career would be financed by government funds!
是, 但你却知道哪个职业会有政府投资！
You could have come over with me. We are friends. You can join us.
你可以跟我一起来的啊, 我们是朋友, 你可以加入我们
Yes, and worked as Miss Kelly's assistant perhaps
是, 可以去当 Kelly 小姐的助手
You know I respect your work very much, Professor Eldred. We would have welcomed you on T-Mat.
你知道我一直都非常敬仰你的工作, Eldred 教授．我们一直都欢迎你加入 T-Mat
I prefer rockets, obsolete as they are!
我还是喜欢火箭, 不管它有多么过时！
Not so obsolete as all that, eh? We don't miss very much, you know.
也不是那么过时, 也许？我们没有失去太多, 你知道fixme
- So you've been spying on me!
- No, no no, we stopped that a long time ago.
- 看来你一直在监视我！  - 不, 不不, 我们很久以前就停掉了
Don't you think so? What's wrong with running a private museum?
(I should think so??) 办一个私人博物馆有什么错？fixme
Nothing, but you're doing rather more than that, aren't you?
没什么错．但你办的不止是这个, 对不？
Alright, What if I am? It's a free country, isn't it? What's wrong with having a hobby?
好吧, 如果不止又怎么样？这是个只有的国家, 对吧？有一点个人爱好有什么错？
Rather more than a hobby -
不只是一点个人爱好
preparing an ion rocket for an unauthorised journey into space!
你是在准备离子火箭, 想用它未经许可就到太空去
All right, so you know.
好吧, 看来你知道
What do you intend to do?
你打算做什么？
- My dear fellow, help you, of course!  - What?
- 我亲爱的伙计, 当然是帮助你  - 什么？
You can make your trip
你可以成行
- as long as it's to the moon.
- Why the moon?
- 只要目的地是月球  - 为什么是月球？
There's a minor fault developed at T-Mat Control at Moonbase.
在月球基地的 T-Mat 控制中心出现了一点小故障
- And we had to put it right, quickly.
- I thought T-Mat was infallible!
- 我们必须得修复它, 还得快  - 我还以为 T-Mat 是绝不出错的
It will be eventually, however we have no way of reaching the moon.
最终会的．目前而言, 我们没有办法到月球上去
Except by out-of-date rocket! Oh, that's perfect!
除非乘坐过时的火箭！哦, 太完美了！
You need me after all (!)
你最终还是需要我！
I thought you'd be taken with the idea,
我觉得你会喜欢这个想法
and a large sum of government funds wouldn't come amiss, would they?
而且一大笔政府资金也不会花错地方, 是吧？
Now, how soon can you be ready to...blast off?
现在说是, 你最快多久可以准备好...发射？
Well, come on, it's urgent! Can you give me an approximate ETD?
诶, 得了, 这是很紧急！你能给我一个大概的时间点吗？
I could, but I won't.
我能, 但我不会给
Why? There are no strings!
为什么？这里没有全套！
I don’t have to give you my reasons. I'm just telling you that I refuse!
我没有必要给出我的理由, 我只告诉你, 我拒绝！
- Right, that should do it.
- I'll switch on the power.
- 好, 这应该可以了  - 我去打开电源
You fools! When they find out, we'll all be killed!
你个蠢人！如果他们发现了, 我们都会被杀掉！
Moonbase to T-Mat Reception Earth.
月球基地呼叫 T-Mat 地球接收站
Moonbase to Earth.
月球基地呼叫地球
Emergency! Emergency!
紧急情况！紧急情况！
You can't refuse man. There’s more at stake here than an out-of-date rocket programme!
你不能拒绝我．这里牵扯在内的不仅仅只是一个过时的火箭计划
- Commander Radnor.
- Excuse me.
- 指挥官 Radnor  - 抱歉
Radnor. Emergency message from Moonbase linking through now.
Radnor．月球基地请求建立紧急消息连接
Commander Radnor, Miss Kelly...
Radnor 指挥官, Kelly 小姐
..we are in desperate trouble! Osgood is dead and we are...
..我们陷入了大麻烦！Osgood 已经死了, 而我们...
Locke! Locke!
Guard!
警卫！
Kill him!
杀了他！
(TRILLING BUZZ)
(part1 ends here)